Mr. Hanlin CAI

Systems Engineering Intern Website: caihanlin.com

Github: github.com/guanglun2000

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Highly motivated and cooperative undergraduate majoring in automation, applying for a Systems Engineering Intern position at EVgo. Well-equipped to leverage my working knowledge of embedded system, Python, Arduino, power supply and experience in electronic troubleshooting activities to contribute to the success of EVgo's mission.

EDUCATION

Fuzhou University (China-Ireland Cooperative Program, Full time at FZU)

Fuzhou, China

Bachelor of Engineering - Automation: CGPA: 3.82/4.00: Rank: 5/60 Bachelor of Science - Robotics and Intelligent Devices (Maynooth University, Ireland, Combined Degrees)

Sep 2020 - June 2024

Email: hanlin.cai@ieee.org

Mobile: (+86) 159-0592-5789

Location: Fuzhou, Fujian (350108)

Courses (All 4.00): Control System, Digital Systems, Embedded Systems, Signal Processing, System Dynamics, Algorithms and Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Operating System, Engineering Mathematics, Differential Equations, Physics for Engineers

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Programming: Python, MATLAB, JAVA, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Bash Tools: GIT, Docker, Conda, Jupyter, Stata, Navicat, OBS, LATEX, EndNote • Platforms: Linux, macOS, Windows, Web, ROS, Cloud, Arduino, Raspberry Pi • Languages: English (Fluent), Mandarin (Native), Hokkien (Native), Japanese (Basic) • Soft Skills: Leadership, Public Speaking, Time Management, Pressure Management

EXPERIENCE

Huading Intelligent Manufacturing Technology Co. LTD

Offline

Embedded Development Intern (Full-time, supervised by SN.ENGR Yuxiong Xia)

Feb 2023 - Present

- o Cloud Database: Designed a Cloud database to store the data collected by various sensors in industrial scenarios.
- Data Visualization: Utilized JavaScript framework to visualize the instrumentation data on client management panel.
- Ratchet PHP WebSocket: Implemented a WebSocket for low-latency real time exchange of posts and thread updates.
- Key Lab of Industrial Automation Control Technology and Information Processing

Offline

Research Assistant (Full-time, supervised by Prof. Zhezhuang Xu)

Dec 2022 - Present

- RMS Testbed: Establish and improve a Real-time Monitoring System (RMS) Testbed for IoT cybersecurity research.
- Detection Algorithm: Designed a supervised learning algorithm to identify and classify malicious network traffic.
- o Management: Collaborate with Prof. Xu to manage and tutor 6 freshmen & sophomore members in our laboratory.

Publications

- Deep Residual Neural Network for Efficient Traffic Sign Detection, First Author: Accepted by 2023 International Conference on Artificial Life and Robotics (ICAROB 28th), advised by Dr. Chin Hong Wong and Dr. Wei Hong Lim.
- An IoT Garbage Monitoring System for Effective Garbage Management, First Author: Accepted by 2022 International Conference on Computer Engineering, Network and Intelligent Multimedia, advised by Dr. Chin Hong Wong.
- RMS Testbed for IoT Cybersecurity Using Machine Learning Based Approach, First Author: Working paper, advised by Prof. Zhezhuang Xu and Dr. Chin Hong Wong, still under working and expect to be finalized in May 2023.

Honors and Awards

- First Prize Scholarship (Three Times, \\ \frac{\pma}{15000*3}\), Second Prize Scholarship (One Time, \\ \frac{\pma}{10000}\)) of FZU
- First Prize (Fujian Competition Area) in China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling Dec, 2022
- Best Student Project of Maynooth International Engineering College in Academic Year (Teamwork) Oct, 2022
- Third Prize in China National College Student Computer Design Competition (Electronic Track) Aug, 2022
- Champion of 100-meter Freestyle Swimming Competition of Fuzhou University June, 2022

Volunteer Experience

Deputy President of Volunteer Department, Youth League Committee of FZU Fuzhou, China Took charge of the planning, operation, and publicity of FZU's volunteer service work. Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

Top 10 Best Volunteers (Only 10/30000) of the year 2021-2022 at FZU Fuzhou, China Organized 39 activities, personal volunteer service time exceeded 240 hours in this year. May 2021 - May 2022

Outstanding Volunteer in 44th Session of the World Heritage Committee Fuzhou, China During the committee, responsible for 11 volunteer activities with over 890 participants. June 2021 - July 2021